Guide to the Bunnell family papers, 1887-1937
Bunnell family papers, 1887-1937
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bunnell family papers, 1887-1937
3875
Bunnell family
.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diary, sketches, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Contains letters from Catharine Sterling Bunnell to her parents describing her activities as an archeology student and her travels in Europe, the Middle East, and elsewhere. Also contains papers of her mother, Katherine S. Day, and sketches by Bella (Dollabella) Day.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters, 1930-1937, from Catharine Sterling Bunnell to her parents describe her studies, work, and social activities as an archeology graduate student at the University of Michigan and the American School of Classical Studies at Athens; her travels in Egypt, Palestine, Syria, Turkey, Romania, Hungary, Austria, Germany, and Canada; studies and social activities at secretarial school in Berkeley, California; and travel to Hawaii and Alaska. There is also a long letter and a typescript paper describing conditions in Egypt. Miss Bunnell's correspondence includes references to her future husband, A. Henry Detweiler, Professor of Architecture at Cornell University, whom she met in Athens. Papers of her mother, Katherine S. Day, include a travel diary and photograph album of a trip to Europe, 1900, and a diary kept during a world's fair, ca. 1903. There are also pencil sketches by Bella (Dollabella) Day, ca. 1887, and a sketchbook.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bunnell family.; Bunnell, Katherine S. Day.; Day, Dollabella.; Detweiler, A. Henry (Albert Henry), 1906-1970.; Detweiler, Catharine Bunnell.; University of Michigan--Students.; American School of Classical Studies at Athens--Students.
Subjects:
Archeologists.
Places:
Alaska--Description and travel.; Austria--Description and travel.; Canada--Description and travel.; Egypt--Description and travel.; Germany--Description and travel.; Hawaii--Description and travel.; Hungary--Description and travel.; Palestine--Description and travel.; Romania--Description and travel.; Syria--Description and travel.; Turkey--Description and travel.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Sketches.; Sketchbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- June - September 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- October 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- November - December 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- January - March 1932 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- April - November 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- January - March 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- April - June 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- July - September 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- October - December 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- January - March 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- April - July 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- August - December 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- About Egypt (to Mrs. Snyder), April 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Modern Egypt, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Sketches, ca. 1887 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sketch book, ca. 1887 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Katherine S. Day Diary, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Katherine S. Day Diary, ca. 1903 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Photograph album, 1900 (Folder 22, Box 1)